Bobby: A good maths teacher, I believe, has confidence in their students because
if a student gets something wrong, if a teacher suddenly puts their hand on their heads and go,
‘Oh God, what have you done?’,
then that child is going to lose their own ability to believe in themselves.
A good teacher will be someone that will encourage them, but at the same time,
try to bring the subject to life.
Bobby: To get students to enjoy maths, one element is something called gamification,
where young people nowadays, they love the idea of competitions and games.
And again, they use social-media apps and they try and get streaks on Snapchat
where they respond to each other every day.
So if you can capture that a little bit.
Again with my students, we use apps and games where at the end of a lesson,
we might have this, er, challenge where five questions, er, options A to D,
students work in twos or threes. And then I’ll put the question up,
and they’ve got to quickly as a team work out the answer.
Bobby: And imagine you’ve got a job interview, and your bus normally takes 30 minutes.
Again, you might think on a normal day, you might just leave 30 minutes.
But actually, you might need to leave 15 minutes of waiting for the bus.
And because we’re in busy London, lots of buses, there might be delays, breakdowns,
you add, let’s say an additional 15 minutes. It takes an hour.
And that conversation that we’ve had is actually practical maths in everyday use.
And you might think it’s just intuition,
but you are using numbers to plan your journey, like all these people here.
They’ve all got somewhere to be, whether it’s lunch or going to a work meeting,
or picking up some shopping.
All of them are planning and using numbers as part of their journey.
So, the next time someone says to you, ‘I don’t use maths’ – yes, you do.
All of us use maths in everyday life.